# Jonathan Bradet-Legris

Phone:  $1-506-860-0110 \mid \text{email: } \underline{\text{jbradetlegris@outlook.com}} \mid \text{Address: Halifax, NS, Canada LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-bradet-legris} \mid \underline{\text{Github: github.com/JonathanB-L}}$ 

With one year business experience as a data scientist, experience in interdisciplinary research, and a wide educational background split between applied and pure mathematics, programming, and life sciences, I've demonstrated to be a fast learner capable of quickly adapting to new projects. I'm seeking to continue advancing my career as a data scientist in a position that will also provide me with the opportunity and challenge to further develop my skills.

## EDUCATION

MSc in Statistics

Sept. 2018 – Dec. 2020

Dalhousie University, (3.9 GPA)

BSc in Mathematics, Minors in Computer Science and Biochemistry

Sept. 2013 – April 2018

Mount Allison University, (3.8 GPA)

SKILLS

Languages: R, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, java.

Version Control: Git.

Data Visualization: Tableau, ggplot2.

Other tools: R Markdown, LaTeX, Altervx (Core certification), Excel.

IDEs: RStudio, VS Code, Jupyter Notebook, SQL Server Management Studio, Eclipse.

# EXPERIENCE

# Data Scientist (Contract)

Aug. 2021 – Aug. 2022

Eastlink

Halifax, NS

- Responsible for conducting data analysis projects and showing result to stakeholders with clear data visualization.
- Major projects included customer segmentation and a predictive model for finding new buyers of smart home services.
- Working with python and SQL on a daily basis, whether updating legacy code or coding entirely new projects.

## Data Analyst (Contract)

Feb. 2021 - March 2021

Dalhousie University

Halifax, NS

• Was responsible for doing data analysis on at-risk bird species data and developing species distribution models. Results were used to inform the forestry industry and conservation efforts in Nova Scotia.

## Master's Degree

Sept. 2018 - Dec. 2020

 $Dalhousie\ University$ 

Halifax, NS

- Developed species distribution models of phytoplankton in the Pacific Ocean using a number of statistical methods, including: linear regression, LASSO, generalized additive models, machine learning, Bayesian linear regression.
- Extensive experience with modeling, data manipulation in R and data visualization using ggplot2.

#### Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2018 – Dec. 2020

 $Dalhousie\ University$ 

Halifax, NS

- Prepared and taught weekly tutorials, condensing a week's worth of material into a 50 minute review session with strong positive feedback from students.
- Worked in the University's help center, assisting students with a variety of subjects in math.

## Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sept. 2013 – April 2018

Mount Allison University

Sackville, NB

- Performed research in abstract mathematics and presented results at academic conferences.
- Created an agent-based model to simulate the spread of lyme disease between ticks and mammal populations.
- Designed an executed an ecology experiment according to given objectives and budget.
- Performed a variety of other tasks such as field work, data entry, assisting with DNA tests, and maintaining lab supplies.

# Veterinary Assistant

Tantramar Veterinary Hospital

May 2016 - Aug 2016 Sackville, NB

• Responsibilities included: clerical duties, cleaning, counting inventory, and assisting the veterinarian and technician with procedures.

# McDonald's Crew Memeber

May 2015 - Aug 2015

McDonald 's

Sackville, NB

• Worked with a team in a fast pace environment to provide food to customers in a timely manner.

# LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and French (reading, writing, and speaking).